<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Halcyon London International School</title>
	<atom:link href="https://halcyonschool.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://halcyonschool.com</link>
	<description>Inspired by Halcyon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 13:47:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cropped-Untitled-design-8-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Halcyon London International School</title>
	<link>https://halcyonschool.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Culture Wars and Schools</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/culture-wars-and-schools/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leeman Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 08:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=15275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As an international school leader, in a vibrant, multicultural city, it’s fair to say that I meet parents, students and staff with incredibly diverse outlooks and opinions. Identity is decidedly not homogeneous. Part of my job is to navigate the many currents that this difference generates, while providing enough commonality and consensus that everyone can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="341" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1-1024x341.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15290" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1-1024x341.png 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1-300x100.png 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1-768x256.png 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1-600x200.png 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>As an international school leader, in a vibrant, multicultural city, it’s fair to say that I meet parents, students and staff with incredibly diverse outlooks and opinions. Identity is decidedly<em> not</em> homogeneous. Part of my job is to navigate the many currents that this difference generates, while providing enough commonality and consensus that everyone can enjoy a sense of belonging: that we can build an effective learning community together.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Challenges</strong></p>



<p>Probably, everyone in my position would like to think that they are good at managing difference &#8211; that it’s a non-negotiable leadership skill, an essential piece of soft politics; however, there’s the potential for a lot of hubris here, and there are plenty of examples of those who fail to do this successfully. And the slow fragmentation of political consensus, and the noise of the ‘culture war’ and its attendant shifting moral sands, means building consensus has become a more uncertain game than ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Firstly, we all know that the landscape is changing. Secondly, like it or not, moral codes do change over time (which is not to say that there’s no value in having a moral compass). In important ways, my moral sensibilities and the imperatives which spring from these, differ from my parents and grandparents. In simple terms, while Twitter and Fox debate pronouns, my<em> great </em>grandparents’ would have worried that it would have been unseemly for a man to be outdoors without a hat, and have understood the social requirement for a respectable woman to wear a headscarf. When changes are measured over a century, they are substantive; over longer periods, they appear inevitable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every so often, there’s an accelerant added to the mix: maybe a previously settled question is challenged or acquires new significance, or a new ideology disrupts the political and public space? In the American context, the remedy for the foundational sin of slavery has never been a settled question, and the broader agenda of social justice, and what we might loosely call identity politics, has unravelled an already frayed political consensus. To quote the Italian philosopher Antonio Gramsci, there is an argument that ‘the old world is dying, and the new world struggles to be born.’ There is a widespread sense that moral and ethical codes are shifting; that we are in between times &#8211; travelling, but not sure of the destination.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This culture war is not the first &#8211; even the name is stolen from the German Kulturkampf of the 1870s &#8211; and it is not the last. In its outlines, it is also not so different from its predecessors, which always centre on conflicts over access to power. For many young people today there is an immediate and necessary struggle to reform society, and to reframe who holds power and how authority is exercised: unsurprisingly, they want to shape the world they want to grow into. But this is not an agreed consensus: to others, these changes can be disconcerting, and they might disagree with some or all of this new ideology; they might wish to meet protest with counter-protest. Somewhere in this contested place, each school will need to find a shared path for their community.</p>



<p>In the U.S., education has become a political battleground, with very public, and different, interventions in school systems and university campuses. Some of this has arrived in the U.K., mainly around questions of gender identity, while one Conservative government minister has tried to bring the argument against <a href="https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/kemi-badenoch-the-problem-with-critical-race-theory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Critical Race Theory</a> to the political centre. The same U.K. government has also found it necessary to issue advice about <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/political-impartiality-in-schools/political-impartiality-in-schools" target="_blank" rel="noopener">impartiality in schools</a>, a document which may have been intended as part emollient and part an exercise in boundary-setting; however, as almost everyone with an inkling of common sense knew would be the case, it swiftly became just another artefact in a divisive and increasingly intolerant political debate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With the strident opinions of politicians and the click-bait of social media driving division, many of us in public-facing roles may wonder how we can plot a successful pathway through what could be a career-ending minefield of righteous expectations and political pressures. While our teachers might be confident that they are sophisticated enough to teach impartially, sometimes they are not &#8211; because this is a quality of being human. But their efforts to find a middle ground count for very little if their critics lack both the emotional intelligence to allow that people are complex and flawed, and the wisdom to accept that no-one has the right answer. This quickness to judgement is both a consequence and a function of polarisation, so much so that at times you might even consider this debate to be a category error; that it is less about politics and more about philosophy, and our endless quest to touch the divine &#8211; to perceive a more perfect reality or truth or justice.</p>



<p><strong>Solutions</strong></p>



<p>If that sounds too much like hot air, let’s ground ourselves by remembering that good schools are good schools because they know how to manage change and uncertainty. Good teachers also know that as children experience the transition into adulthood, everything in the world is glimpsed for the first time, and they own the excitement and ecstasy of discovering this rich new land in a way their parents could never understand. And some fall in love with politics for the first time, and their experience of this is thrilling, illuminating, electrifying: they are energised and empowered, and have the pride and confidence and narcissism of youth, untested and certain. They do not have the responsibilities or weariness of the adult world, and can be faithful only to themselves and their ideals. This is a liberating place to be, and good schools and teachers know, mostly, how to navigate this and how to allow this energy to be creative and thoughtful and productive.</p>



<p>In our school, we think that we have managed to embrace the essential <em>zeitgeist </em>of change, but not be muddied by its politics. Because our teachers know how change works, and are unafraid of this, we can allow students to experience the joy of discovery. We can support this by fostering a spirit of fearless critical inquiry. And by teaching citizenship skills, students have the political literacy to be able to go out into the world and exercise democratic power and advocate for their views. These are all essential life skills, whatever your beliefs about the world.</p>



<p>Our school is also human-centred, which approach supports students&#8217; social and emotional development, and so their agency, sense of belonging, and well-being. We learn to care about each other, which means developing empathy and compassion, and the ability to serve others (while so many talk about leadership, though we teach that too). We &#8211; school leaders and teachers and governors &#8211; need to spend more time learning about ourselves, too, and then have the humility to realise how much baggage we might be trailing behind us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the process of reviewing our approach to diversity and inclusion, one of our teachers advocated the idea of <a href="https://www.northeastern.edu/graduate/blog/culturally-responsive-teaching-strategies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">culturally responsive teaching</a>, a methodology that requires nothing more political than a willingness to learn about, and value, others. It asks that every student can see themselves reflected in the curriculum, and in the library services, and in the extra- and co-curriculars, and in the way we present ourselves, and organise our building. To not do this would be to make an intentional decision to alienate someone, and who would want to do this?</p>



<p>A colleague in another school, in Atlanta, suggested that we support staff to be more culturally competent &#8211; that we provide professional training to develop our community’s <a href="https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000219768" target="_blank" rel="noopener">intercultural competence</a>. This is not a new idea &#8211; we are a successful International Baccalaureate school, whose mission includes a commitment to ‘intercultural understanding and respect’ &#8211; but it is not always obvious how best to develop these social skills, and we needed to make space for this in our school. But it’s not much more complicated than asking that each of us spends time being more aware of our own cultural lens; that we recognise that our worldview is only one way of understanding the people around us and the different worlds they belong to; that others may well be right, even about things that really matter to us; and that we can each strive to be adaptable enough to respect and explore and embrace the diversity around us. To not do this would mean I would have to make a very intentional decision to require everyone else to meet me where I am, and nowhere else. Who would embrace such condescension?&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Perspectives</strong></p>



<p>There are many ironies that bedevil this discussion. Sometimes forgotten in the American discussion of colonialism, is that the reach of American soft power includes the imposition of many of America’s cultural values and expectations &#8211; including the expectation that other cultures accept particular ideas of social justice. This is how it’s always been: dominant powers have always used their mercantile strength to trade only with those who support their interests, and to force change on weaker states in exchange for access. The demand that another polity acquiesce to a particular economic programme, or change its political process or even its leaders, is a familiar trope of imperial power, past and present; in the context of what we think of as <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p0054594" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the American Century</a>, <em>pax americana </em>extended this to the rights revolution, a process that I might understate as not being without irony.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you live in the English-speaking world, the dominance of American culture and ideas is unavoidable, delivered through hard realities and soft political power, including tech companies, social media, streaming services, creative industries, and so on. American concerns inevitably become ours, too. And of course, plenty of American history is also English history, and so we have some shared responsibilities. None of this is easy to parse.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In trying to decode the complexities of the culture war, nothing is as one-eyed and simplistic as those on the political extremes would have us believe. A culture war is, by definition, a place of chronic disagreement, where certainties can be misplaced or erased, and extremists and populists can find an audience. Gramsci saw this time between changing worlds as a place of chaos, when ‘a great many morbid symptoms appear’. This is more colourfully translated as ‘a time of monsters’, and Gramsci’s monsters were embodied by the fascism of the 1930s. (Stalin was another monster, but Gramsci put this aside; he was writing as a communist sitting in Mussolini’s jail). The current intolerance that accompanies deep political polarisation is a place where monsters might be born.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In these particularly uncertain times, it takes a great deal of confidence, or hubris, or arrogance for anyone, let alone a school leader, to assume they have the right answer, and to then believe they have the moral authority to impose this on others. But school leaders do have to lead, and the process of learning is not without choice and bias. It is a difficult but profound responsibility: school leaders owe it to every child to support compassionate discourse and critical inquiry, and to allow everyone to be recognised, understood and valued. And, somehow, we need to keep the politics and the monsters out of the room.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Navigating middle years education</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/navigatingmiddleyearseducation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leeman Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 13:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=15053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In January our School Director Barry Mansfield visited the Bloomberg European HQ in the City of London. Alongside Preethi Nair (Author, Keynote Speaker, MD), Barry discussed navigating the middle years with employees at Bloomberg focusing on human centered approach and insights into managing a child&#8217;s education. Many Bloomberg employees had further questions and Barry has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="341" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5-1024x341.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15054" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5-1024x341.png 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5-300x100.png 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5-768x256.png 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5-600x200.png 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>In January our School Director <a href="mailto:bmansfield@halcyonschool.com">Barry Mansfield</a> visited the Bloomberg European HQ in the City of London. Alongside Preethi Nair (Author, Keynote Speaker, MD), Barry discussed navigating the middle years with employees at Bloomberg focusing on human centered approach and insights into managing a child&#8217;s education. Many Bloomberg employees had further questions and Barry has prepared a response to these questions.</p>



<p><strong><span style="color:#000aa3" class="has-inline-color">Student Wellbeing</span></strong></p>



<p>Well-being can be understood in different ways, but in school settings, it is most often described as a remedy (often counselling) for a problem (often related to mental health). One could be forgiven for thinking that a well-being need is really the same as a mental health need. That would not be how we think of well-being. Nor do we think of it as a quasi-medical term, such as a well-being clinic that will put you back on track.</p>



<p>While there is always a need for appropriate support services, we think there’s a better way to approach wellbeing. When we teach wellbeing we are learning a positive mix of personal, and institutional, wellness: a set of skills, dispositions, behaviours and habits of</p>



<p>mind that can be practised and mastered so that each student is empowered with the social and emotional skills to feel fulfilled and have meaning in both every day and the extraordinary. Wellbeing is about having intellectual, social and emotional security, where students and staff can learn how to navigate challenges and where they have a voice and agency in decisions that impact upon them. Where they feel recognised for who they are and have a&nbsp; sense of belonging.</p>



<p>We teach cognitive coaching, which provides students and staff with a process to support reflection and help mediate thinking &#8211; teaching thinking and problem-solving skills. Restorative practice builds relationships, so punitive sanctions are replaced with mediation, building key social skills: empathy, compassion, and listening skills. This restores broken relationships and builds community and belonging. Specifically, bullying is managed in this way: giving voice to the victim and ensuring the aggressor is confronted with the consequences of their behaviour. In general terms, this process is intensive and requires investment from the school, but our evidence is that it is inclusive and improves behaviour.</p>



<p>Well-being is about having power and agency, coupled with responsibility and accountability. Our purpose is not just about passing examinations: it is to send young people out into the world with the confidence and skills they need to be purposeful, active members of society, and to be changemakers if that’s what they want. This means nurturing independence at school, so students learn the processes of civic engagement, the political literacies that allow them to negotiate and compromise and lead and, ultimately, have meaning in what they do. Independence means allowing students to run student-led conferences; providing students with access to staff meetings, and giving them a voice in processes that impact them. We are also a very digital school, so we embrace essential technologies that allow students to navigate their world. So, we don’t ban mobile phones; we learn how to use them responsibly.</p>



<p>We have small class sizes (16 as a maximum), but we recognise that we are an independent school and have made a decision to be that way; not every school has this choice and/or can afford to do this. Class size does matter, though, not only for academic reasons: this is also the key driver of relationships, which are so necessary to a sense of belonging and status in school.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><span style="color:#001ca3" class="has-inline-color">DEI</span></strong></p>



<p>Always ask questions that matter to you and your child, and be sure you have good, evidenced answers. Beyond this, you could ask about any of the following.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The school should have a DEI strategy, which someone can talk through with you. Ask about the school’s main concerns, how they intend to address these, and what success looks like. Ask what progress they made last year, and what the goals are this year. There should be some evidence for this, too, so ask to see that. For example, this year, in our school, we have a new student-led DEI conference examining how students manage difficult conversations; and, all staff are completing a second round of training in intercultural competency. Last year, we completed a full review of our curriculum, examining the cultural responsiveness of our teaching and learning spaces.<br></li><li>There should be training for staff so that they can lead culturally responsive classrooms. This idea &#8211;&nbsp; being culturally responsive &#8211; is about recognising differences in individuals in the classroom, and ensuring every child, no matter their identity can see themselves reflected in the curriculum. This allows children to belong and supports their well-being.<br></li><li>Look for a visible commitment to DEI. If staffing seems to over-represent a particular group or the curriculum is overly centred on a particular place or time or people, or you just feel out-of-place, then raise these questions. Ask about the curriculum, to find out what is taught and what has been omitted, and then question those choices. Every school should have a purposeful rationale for why they teach something, or not, and should be pleased to share this information.<br></li><li>Talk with students and ask them about diversity in the school, and what the school does to ensure that everyone feels recognised. Ask them what happens in the school when someone is accused of racism (or misogyny, harassment, or bullying). Ask them if they are consulted about DEI matters; if not, then ask the staff team why students are not involved.</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="color:#0300a3" class="has-inline-color">School culture</span></strong></p>



<p>If we consider<em> the opposite</em> of Restorative practice, which would be rules and consequences (or crime and punishment), it helps us understand what needs to change.</p>



<p>Rules are inflexible, and designed this way so that individuals cannot make changes: they provide systems that are supposed to save time (human resources) and ‘automate’ how we interact with each other. Some of this is plainly not true though, and rules have a habit of creating other rules until the culture of a school&nbsp; &#8211; or a business &#8211; is less about people and more about systems, which take more and more time to manage. We end up managing the system rather than managing people. Restorative practice is one way we can reverse this unhealthy culture and be human-centred instead.</p>



<p>And, don’t have rigid consequences, because almost all school misbehaviour will be minor enough to meditate, and all of it will be rooted in problems that are entirely unrelated to the immediate issues and any pre-ordained consequence. Automated consequences remove the opportunity to explore and resolve these issues.</p>



<p>Instead of having rules, have principles or values; and instead of having rigid consequences, have mediation. Restorative practice involves spending time with young people to help them understand themselves, understand their motivations and actions, and understand their responsibilities; it involves spending time with those who have been ‘wronged’, hearing their stories and giving them an opportunity to share this with whoever it is who has caused them pain or hurt or discomfort. This takes practice and training, but it rebuilds broken relationships and allows students to have ownership of their social and emotional learning. It is incredibly powerful: my experience with students is that on almost every occasion if they are empowered with responsibility then they step-up; if they are beaten down with systems and rules, then they withdraw and are more likely to embrace an identity that purposefully alienates them from the community.</p>



<p>Also learn how to use a phone responsibly. It is probably the single most powerful item you own: the aggregated knowledge of most of humanity is available on your phone, and it has tools that we use every day to help us navigate the world. Students need to know how to use them, so we use them in the classroom. We also know the safeguarding concerns around phones, and anxieties about social media, but these need to be addressed, and students need strategies to manage these questions.  School should be the place to do this; banning phones would be evidence of adults (schools) avoiding their responsibilities. And, it’s worth saying that our examination results are excellent: there is a correlation between mobile phones and academic outcomes</p>



<p><strong><span style="color:#0018a3" class="has-inline-color">Qualifications &amp; Citizenship</span></strong></p>



<p>The IB has a core <a href="https://www.ibo.org/benefits/learner-profile/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Learner Profile</a> that is a natural focus for us. We also mandate that every student provides some service to the community, either internally (for younger students) or externally: social responsibility is taken seriously enough that students cannot receive their IB Diploma unless they complete their service. The IB also demands that all subjects are contextualised &#8211; made relevant to the world around us &#8211; so students build citizenship skills through the application of their understandings.</p>



<p>We have a range of co-curricular activities and an institutional practice that provide the basis for social/emotional learning, and this allows students to develop their ‘soft skills’; for example, students regularly present at staff meetings, and will attend Senior leadership meetings, and sit on teacher interview panels. These are essential life skills.</p>



<p><strong><span style="color:#0006a3" class="has-inline-color">School Development</span></strong></p>



<p>We are still growing as a community, and we’d like to open a primary school. We’d hope to do this in the next 3 or 4 years. We have some information about our <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/strategic-plan-2020-21/">strategic plan</a> on our website. I’d direct interested families to our website: we have a lot of extra- and co-curricular activities, and the usual support services for language learners and other educational needs.</p>



<p><strong>To find out more about Halcyon London International School, contact us at <a href="mailto:join@halcyonschool.com">join@halcyonschool.com</a> or call <a href="tel:+44 (0)20 7258 1169">+44 (0)20 7258 1169</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Halcyon Bursary Programme</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/the-halcyon-bursary-programme/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leeman Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 12:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=14759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Halcyon London International was created as London’s only not-for-profit IB school. Through a pioneering educational programme, our mission is to draw out the unique potential of each student. Our Bursary Programme allows us to support students who otherwise might not be able to access a Halcyon education.&#160; Christabel, whose child Finley benefited from a Halcyon [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="341" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-1-1024x341.png" alt="" class="wp-image-14768" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-1-1024x341.png 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-1-300x100.png 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-1-768x256.png 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-1-600x200.png 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-1.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Halcyon London International was created as London’s only not-for-profit IB school. Through a pioneering educational programme, our mission is to draw out the unique potential of each student. Our Bursary Programme allows us to support students who otherwise might not be able to access a Halcyon education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Christabel, whose child Finley benefited from a Halcyon bursary, talked to us about her experience.</p>



<p><strong>What does the Halcyon Bursary Programme mean to you and your family?</strong></p>



<p>It was an absolute lifesaver for us. He would not be the person he is today or have the opportunities he has now without the help of the Bursary Programme. I would like to thank all the families who generously donated to the Bursary Programme and allowed Finley to finish his Halcyon education.</p>



<p><strong>What was the value of Halcyon education to Finley?</strong></p>



<p>Halcyon helped shape Finely into the person he is today. Being at an IB school with a close-knit community instilled in him strong self-confidence, and since everyone knew each other, he was able to develop real friendships that he still maintains today. Halcyon not only gave Finley a fantastic education, but it also introduced him to a truly international community that broadened his horizons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a family, we also liked that the IB is internationally recognised and that many universities prefer it to other systems. Finley is currently studying Chemistry and Natural Sciences at Minerva University in San Francisco, so the IB was definitely the best choice.</p>



<p><strong>During Finley’s time at Halcyon, what qualities and skills did he develop?</strong></p>



<p>The way Halcyon teachers encourage students to take charge of their learning helped Finely become an independent thinker and to evaluate things critically from an all-round perspective. Given the holistic nature of the IB curriculum, Finley learned to use multi-disciplinary thinking to solve problems and answer big questions. He particularly enjoyed the Theory of Knowledge component, and as a family, we liked how Halcyon enhances the CAS element in their daily culture. Moreover, Halcyon taught Finley the value of being a global citizen. For example, he participated in extracurricular activities related to environmental sciences, and thanks to the effort teachers put in, Finley developed a strong interest in ecology and the environment.</p>



<p>Another element that we loved about Halcyon was the wellbeing culture present in the school. At Halcyon, Finley knew that anytime he needed help, either academic or pastoral-care related, he would receive the necessary support. All members of staff are trained in cognitive coaching, so they facilitate respectful, deep and productive relationships in the community. Finley now works part-time as an online tutor and uses many of the listening and communicating techniques he learnt during his time at Halcyon.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://mail.google.com/mail/u/0?ui=2&amp;ik=ea573a88d6&amp;attid=0.1&amp;permmsgid=msg-f:1757435727486935429&amp;th=1863aa7b9c706185&amp;view=fimg&amp;fur=ip&amp;sz=s0-l75-ft&amp;attbid=ANGjdJ8KyfxlCvdv6FAUvwHxH4qKD3hxaaFIdLxx5atoinxxmzmuOsfxGt6eNnV2emZRallMID-rF846m3mkRn_CHAjkqDBaHhHBahU-ZWZsLBk9BWiOydSMQkxk2eQ&amp;disp=emb&amp;realattid=1863aa713047c6bce4d1" alt="" width="587" height="440"/></figure></div>



<p><strong>As a parent, what was your favourite part of the Halcyon experience?</strong></p>



<p>I enjoyed the sense of community at Halcyon. The families were welcoming and lovely. It was great because we had just moved from Sydney to London, and Halcyon gave us an instant community. Finley settled in straight away and started making good friends. He loved being in the middle of such a big and exciting city. We were also happy that there was a vegetarian cafeteria on-site, so we knew Finley was eating healthy and delicious food (and no packed lunches to make!).</p>



<p><strong>What would you like to say to families considering donating to the Bursary Programme?</strong></p>



<p>The Bursary Programme is life-changing. By donating, you are helping those within your community and supporting a family who wouldn’t be able to join or continue at Halcyon without it.&nbsp; The Bursary Programme changes the future of families within your school community: it is a gift for a lifetime.</p>



<p><strong>If you were to recommend Halcyon to another family, what would you like them to know about us?</strong></p>



<p>It’s just the most fantastic school! I recommend Halcyon all the time! I think it’s such a rare privilege to be educated in the middle of such an international city like London, and Halcyon utilises the best city spaces and facilities. The way teachers maximise technology with innovative digital tools gave Finley an excellent grounding for his university studies. The teachers are wonderful and foster a warm and supportive environment. We couldn’t have asked for a better school for Finley.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Artificial Intelligence in Schools</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/artificial-intelligence-in-schools/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leeman Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 13:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=14586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many of you will have seen articles and social media posts about ChatGPT over the last month. ChatGPT is an artificial intelligence-powered chatbot made by a company called OpenAI, which is able to respond to natural language input. This means that it can give advice and help you to write many different things, including essays, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="341" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-6-1024x341.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15066" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-6-1024x341.png 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-6-300x100.png 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-6-768x256.png 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-6-600x200.png 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-6.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Many of you will have seen articles and social media posts about ChatGPT over the last month. ChatGPT is an artificial intelligence-powered chatbot made by a company called OpenAI, which is able to respond to natural language input.<br><br>This means that it can give advice and help you to write many different things, including essays, emails, marketing campaigns and poetry. It is freely available online if you would like to explore it. Over the last few weeks, there have been a number of news articles focusing on<br>its ability to produce entire essays that achieve good grades, which has created considerable interest and unease in the education sector. There has been a wide range of responses to this, ranging from curious and excited to terrified and pessimistic (for example, New York has banned the use of it in schools).<br><br>At Halcyon, we are taking a curious, optimistic and critical approach. We know that Artificial Intelligence (AI) isn’t going anywhere and that students will need to know how to work with it and use it as a co-creator in the future. We also know that despite many hasty efforts to fire-fight by building ‘AI detectors’ and banning ChatGPT in schools, this approach is unlikely to work in the long term.</p>



<p>There are new AI tools being introduced on a daily basis which will continue to get more sophisticated and undetectable. Instead of seeing AI as a threat, we hope to:</p>



<p><strong>&#8211; Teach students how to work with AI, see its amazing creative potential and use it where appropriate</strong></p>



<p><strong>&#8211;  Help students to see the value in the process of creating something themselves, rather than just in a finished product and a grade<br></strong><br><strong>&#8211; Think critically about AI and its impact on society, now and in the future &#8211; allowing students to develop AI literacy as a part of the digital literacy curriculum.</strong><br><br>The nature of some assignments and time pressures may mean that despite our best efforts to encourage the positive use of AI, we may also need to set some boundaries with students for how and when it is appropriate to use it. We are already in collaboration with students to find fair and positive solutions.<br><br>We are not quite sure what the future (or even the next year) will bring in terms of AI, but as a school that encourages innovation and aims to prepare students for the future, we are excited to explore it with students. We would also love to hear any parent feedback about ChatGPT and AI and how you feel it might impact students or your workplace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>London’s only not-for-profit IB School: 5 questions to Halcyon London International School co-founder, Rita Halbright</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/londons-only-not-for-profit-ib-school-5-questions-to-halcyon-london-international-school-co-founder-rita-halbright/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leeman Robinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 08:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Baccalaureate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=14538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Given Halcyon&#8217;s commitment to creating a learning environment that supports students to challenge themselves to realise their full potential, we sat down with our co-founder, Rita Halbright, to learn more about Halcyon&#8217;s mission. As a parent and a co-founder of Halcyon, what was your motivation behind creating a not-for-profit IB? We were four parents who [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/image-1-1024x341.png" alt="" class="wp-image-14569" width="1117" height="372" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/image-1-1024x341.png 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/image-1-300x100.png 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/image-1-768x256.png 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/image-1-600x200.png 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/image-1.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1117px) 100vw, 1117px" /></figure>



<p>Given Halcyon&#8217;s commitment to creating a learning environment that supports students to challenge themselves to realise their full potential, we sat down with our co-founder, Rita Halbright, to learn more about Halcyon&#8217;s mission.</p>



<p><strong>As a parent and a co-founder of Halcyon, what was your motivation behind creating a not-for-profit IB?</strong></p>



<p>We were four parents who cared deeply about providing an <a href="https://www.teachingtimes.com/its-time-for-the-uk-government-to-get-real-about-digital-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">innovative education</a>. We wanted Halcyon to reflect what we know today about effective learning communities and not rely on outdated education models. With a blank slate, we could explore best practices and evidence-based models, attract open-minded forward thinking staff, and embrace the best that technology has to offer. We understood that a warm and welcoming environment helps students thrive, engage with their learning, find their voice, and give them agency. We were inspired by a number of educators, for example, Sir Ken Robinson and Sugata Mitra.</p>



<p>We had a number of priorities, but the key ones were to offer an exciting, holistic, student-centred IB education; include varied learning experiences to support the development of a broader toolkit, create a bursary programme, and view the whole school community as life-long learners and partners in the journey. This means &#8211; in addition to educating students &#8211; investing in meaningful and robust <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/coaching/">professional development for staff </a>and learning opportunities for parents. We also wanted to embed into the School’s culture these priorities: student wellbeing, <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/sustainability-at-halcyon/">sustainability</a>, inclusion and diversity and digital skills. We wanted to continue to challenge the status quo to make sure that Halcyon is always questioning and improving, listening and learning, experiencing and engaging, at all levels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, as parents ourselves, we realised that paying for school is an investment in our most valuable asset, our children. We wanted to provide financial transparency to families so it was clear how their fees were being spent. To support this we became a not-for-profit school organised as a charity, investing all fee income back into Halcyon. As part of this, we do our best to include as many expenses in the fees as possible, including <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/sustainability-commitment/">fresh snacks and lunch</a>, an annual residential trip, other day trips, in addition to many extra-curricular activities.</p>



<p><strong>Halcyon’s mission is to provide an exceptional education that draws out the unique potential of each student. Can you share with me how Halcyon challenges students and prepares them for the future?</strong></p>



<p>You just have to look at our inspiring curriculum and meet our engaging students and innovative staff. By committing to no more than 250 students, Halcyon is a tight-knit community where everyone knows everyone. We focus on each student being seen, heard and supported. Research shows that when you feel welcome and included, you have a much better chance to learn and thrive.</p>



<p>In addition to a great IB curriculum, our students in Grade 6 to 9 are stretched through the Exploration programme and their Passion Projects. In preparation for the <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/ib-student-profile/">Diploma Programme</a> at Halcyon, students develop skills in time and project management; collaboration; mentoring; restorative justice practices; mindfulness, and more.</p>



<p>From Grade 6 onwards, students are encouraged to challenge themselves both inside and outside of the classroom. While they are exposed to tremendous content through their subject units,&nbsp; they explore related topics of personal interest to broaden their knowledge and skills.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Halcyon is the only not-for-profit IB in London, what inspired you to take this approach?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Private education is expensive as it is. Parents deserve to know how their fees are being spent. Halcyon was set-up to be a truly not-for-profit and independent international school with its own <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/video-academia-at-halcyon/">distinctive character and ethos</a>, part of which is to ensure financial transparency. And the for-profit model did not match our philosophy about education. Besides the regulatory and accrediting&nbsp; institutions such as Ofsted, the IBO and NEASC, Halcyon is beholden only to its students, the community of staff and parents, and its diverse volunteer board of trustees, not to any corporate entity or owner.</p>



<p><strong>As a not-for-profit IB, why do you feel it’s important to have a bursary programme? How does it align with Halcyon’s ethos?</strong></p>



<p>A huge part of life at Halcyon is to be active, constructive citizens. Thanks to elements of a not-for-profit combined with an IB curriculum, our students see their school investing in public benefit through curricular related activities, volunteer projects and through the bursary programme. The <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/donate/#bursarymission">bursary programme</a> broadens everyone’s perspective, allows us to be more inclusive and encourages our students to seek opportunities to give back as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Halcyon’s bursary programme relies on the generosity of the donors. What would you like to say to them?</strong></p>



<p>Offering a bursary to students who would otherwise be unable to benefit from a Halcyon education not only enriches the recipients, but our entire community. Every gift to our bursary programme &#8211; irrespective of size &#8211; makes a difference, and we are grateful for all contributions.</p>



<p>In short, I believe Halcyon is on track, offering a challenging, forward-looking, holistic education and I believe I speak for my fellow co-founders, Achim, Julie and Pamela.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Year On: A review of Halcyon School from new staff</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/halcyon-school-review/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halcyon London International School]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 13:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Student Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=14220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just as starting at a new school can be a transformative experience for young people, starting a position in a new workplace can bring challenges as well as opportunities for teachers at Halcyon School .&#160; We sat down with three of our 2021 joiners to find out what they have to say about their journey [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Just as starting at a new school can be a transformative experience for young people, starting a position in a new workplace can bring challenges as well as opportunities for teachers at Halcyon School .&nbsp;</p>



<p>We sat down with three of our 2021 joiners to find out what they have to say about their journey at Halcyon so far &#8211; and we couldn’t have been more inspired by what they shared with us. From fond memories of student initiatives to excitement for future projects, the insights we gained from Ms Lodhi, Ms Rautavuori, and Mr Robinson can be treasured by our whole community.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D2_267-1-1024x656.jpeg" alt="halcyon school learning" class="wp-image-14230" width="1083" height="694" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D2_267-1-1024x656.jpeg 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D2_267-1-300x192.jpeg 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D2_267-1-768x492.jpeg 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D2_267-1-1536x985.jpeg 1536w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D2_267-1-600x385.jpeg 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D2_267-1.jpeg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1083px) 100vw, 1083px" /></figure></div>



<h2><strong>Halcyon School&#8217;s Community</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Dr Sabahat Lodhi, IB MYP Science and DP Chemistry Teacher</strong></p>



<p>“Our strength is in our community &#8211; at every level.”</p>



<p>Dr Sabahat Lodhi joined Halcyon in August 2021, teaching students across the whole school and welcoming green-minded young people to our Eco Committee, which she supervises. For Sabahat, the sense of community is what makes Halcyon special.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The staff are supported in the staff community, and new students are welcomed by their peers across all grade groups, which is wonderful to see. It is this sense of connection that drives academic success at Halcyon: when young people feel understood and cared for, they thrive.”</p>



<p>Sabahat is keen to add that this feeling of ‘thriving’ extends to staff as well as students. “It feels like we all embrace the idea of lifelong learning together &#8211; it’s not just something we say, but something we see on a daily basis.”</p>



<p>A commitment to lifelong learning means that our teachers enrol on a variety of <a href="https://www.tes.com/magazine/teaching-learning/general/cognitive-coaching-essential-cpd-teachers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">professional development courses</a>, alongside thinking about the best ways in which they can bring new ideas and initiatives to our school community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sabahat smiles as she begins to divulge more information about her plans for next term. “After COP27, I’ll be working on International Women’s Day for Women and Girls in STEM &#8211; and in true Halcyon style, it’s going to be bigger and better than ever before with students’ help!”</p>



<p>We asked Sabahat about her favourite memories at Halcyon so far. “My favourite memories? There are so many! Our student Eco-Committee is always so full of energy and innovative ideas, and I was particularly blown away in our first meeting &#8211; their ideas and passion to make a difference was incredible.”</p>



<p>As Sabahat continued to tell us about her standout memories of Halcyon, it became clear that Halcyon’s students form an unforgettable part of our teachers’ experiences on campus. “They continue to astound me every session. Our annual debate day &#8211; particularly last year’s event &#8211; as well as last year’s School Show theatre performance will always stay with me: in both events, students demonstrated an incredible amount of enthusiasm and resilience.”&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D1_081-1024x682.jpg" alt="art at halcyon" class="wp-image-14231" width="1410" height="939" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D1_081-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D1_081-300x200.jpg 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D1_081-768x512.jpg 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D1_081-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D1_081-600x400.jpg 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB21_HALCYON_D1_081.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1410px) 100vw, 1410px" /></figure></div>



<h2><strong>Halcyon School&#8217;s Culture</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Sandra Rautavuori, IB MYP PHE Teacher</strong></p>



<p>“At Halcyon, everyone is encouraged to be themselves, and is celebrated for who they are.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sandra Rautavuori, one of our MYP PHE teachers, highlighted Halcyon’s culture as something that she has valued since her very first day at the school.</p>



<p>“Halcyon’s culture is community-based and so accepting. Everyone is friendly &#8211; and it feels really special to know that everyone knows each other in one way or another.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sandra added how Halcyon had encouraged her to think beyond her current responsibilities as PHE teacher to plan how she might add to the life of the community next.</p>



<p>“I’m looking forward to being a mentor this year. Mentoring is a great opportunity to build relationships with students, and, having completed the cognitive coaching course, I’m looking forward to putting what I recently learned into practice. Hopefully I’ll soon be able to see the benefits of this training on students and the community at large.”&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Halcyon School&#8217;s Creativity</h2>



<p><strong>Leeman Robinson, Marketing Leader</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_065-1024x702.jpg" alt="staff at halcyon" class="wp-image-14232" width="1161" height="796" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_065-1024x702.jpg 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_065-300x206.jpg 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_065-768x527.jpg 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_065-1536x1054.jpg 1536w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_065-600x412.jpg 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_065.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1161px) 100vw, 1161px" /></figure></div>



<p>“It’s been a year since I started at Halcyon School, and I remain impressed by the diligence and attention to detail of this relatively new educational institution.”</p>



<p>Leeman Robinson, Halcyon’s Marketing Leader, spent some time with us to reflect on how he felt when he first experienced classroom learning at Halcyon</p>



<p>“I sat in classes and rekindled some lost knowledge of geography, but I also experienced a whole new kind of learning. I learned new things about the use of the English language via the study of film &#8211; something that would never have happened in my own education. When I compare what I experienced in Halcyon classes to my own conventional British education, I felt somewhat cheated!”</p>



<p>Leeman thoughtfully recalls some of his other memories of Halcyon classes. “I visited an IB Spanish class where students were asked to design and create a board game. The instructions were to be written in Spanish, and they had to present back to the class entirely in their language of study &#8211; nothing like my experience of undertaking French at secondary school, which consisted of reciting phrases scribbled on the chalkboard!”</p>



<p>Leeman explains that it is the diverse and engaging teaching styles of Halcyon that make it such a special place to work in &#8211; as well as the dynamic role that the students play in building community life. “I find what students do here really inspiring. They often curate whole-school assemblies, organise fundraisers for charitable causes, and even create costumes for the school show. I’m currently working on a campaign to mark the school’s ten year anniversary, and one student offered to produce a bespoke logo to mark the occasion. It’s wonderful to be surrounded by so much agency from young people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>We asked Leeman to summarise his impressions of Halcyon School. After some thought, he answered, “I am confident that anyone who encounters Halcyon School for the first time will feel that it’s an educational institution like no other.”</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/coaching/">3 reasons why we’re all trained in Cognitive Coaching</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/moving-school/">Moving school: 3 ways our newest students were surprised by their Halcyon experience</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/ib-student-profile/">IB Student Profile: Lola, Grade 12, on the Diploma Programme</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 ways in which Cognitive Coaching boosts university preparation</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/university-preparation-coaching/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halcyon London International School]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 14:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Student Wellbeing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=14106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“What’s significant about Halcyon is that focusing on student wellbeing is central to who we are. It doesn’t come as an afterthought, or an add-on &#8211; with a few extra support services tagged on to an academic curriculum and university preparation facilities- it has been a fundamental and core priority for our school from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>“What’s significant about Halcyon is that focusing on student wellbeing is central to who we are. It doesn’t come as an afterthought, or an add-on &#8211; with a few extra support services tagged on to an academic curriculum and university preparation facilities- it has been a fundamental and core priority for our school from the beginning.”</p>



<p>Asil Al-Shammari, our <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/success/university-and-careers-counselling/">University and Careers Counselling</a> Director, adds the following: “This &#8211; our Cognitive Coaching Programme &#8211; is what equips students to be confident and successful as they consider Higher Education options.”</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_046-1024x682.jpg" alt="university preparation" class="wp-image-14107"/></figure></div>



<h2>Early university preparation: exploring passions, strengths, and interests</h2>



<p>From the very beginning of our Cognitive Coaching programme, starting in Grade 6, our students have the opportunity to plan a successful week at school, and reflect on what might not have gone so well the week before. To do this, students naturally identify their strengths and weaknesses: how they can use their social abilities, for example, to perform better in group work, or how they could improve their organisational skills to succeed academically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During such conversations, students are encouraged to think about what kind of work they enjoy, and what they might want to do more of. This sparking of passions is channeled into Halcyon’s <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/academics/personal-learning/">Personal Learning</a> programme: from Grade 6, a student can develop their research, planning, and evaluation skills by completing a Passion Project on a subject of their choice. Previous passion projects have centred around animation, recipes, and even the practice of law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Starting Cognitive Coaching from early on puts students in the driving seat and moves them away from making choices based on typical narratives that push young learners to think about what they ‘should’ want,” explains Asil. “This makes them far more likely to succeed at whatever they choose to do.”&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="685" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_050-1024x685.jpg" alt="coaching teachers" class="wp-image-14108" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_050-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_050-300x201.jpg 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_050-768x513.jpg 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_050-1536x1027.jpg 1536w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_050-600x401.jpg 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/VB22_HALCYON_FEB_050.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>



<h2>A supportive and uplifting environment</h2>



<p>“There’s a sense that everyone in Grade 12 can be equally successful &#8211; it never feels like a competition between university applicants,” shares Asil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our University and Careers Counselling Director explains that this is a result of the <a href="https://www.teachingtimes.com/our-a-levels-system-isnt-preparing-pupils-for-university-or-life-academically-or-emotionally/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">student-driven nature of university consideration</a> at Halcyon, buttressed by the Cognitive Coaching programme that supports students throughout their entire school journey. Students feel self-assured that they have made the choices that are suitable for their passions, strengths, and goals &#8211; and each individual supports one another in the university application process.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Confidence in academics</h2>



<p>Asil agrees that there is certainly a positive feedback loop that results from students self-assuredness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Because students feel that they are pursuing academic excellence for themselves, rather than for others, there’s less of a sense of pressure when it comes to exam season. Students feel they can focus entirely on their own preparation rather than focusing on the expectations of their peers &#8211; a phenomenon which can sometimes have a counterproductive impact on success.”&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Courage to change paths &#8211; before and after university</h2>



<p>At Halcyon, the Cognitive Coaching programme encourages students to become stronger at self-reflection and evaluation. Without these key skills, some young people &#8211; as well as adults &#8211; may feel unequipped to re-evaluate their choices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Instead of continuing with a path they feel unhappy with, our students are much more likely to change their career goals to something that inspires them more. It is this courage that allows them to choose options at university level in which they can thrive,” explains Asil.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Thinking ahead: careers beyond university</h2>



<p>“Because <a href="https://www.tes.com/magazine/leadership/staff-management/wellbeing-around-world-removing-heads-subjects" target="_blank" rel="noopener">every teacher is trained in Cognitive Coaching</a>, students receive opportunities for self-reflection and planning in the classroom as well as from their mentors,” adds Asil.</p>



<p>Building such capacity across the staff body enables Halcyon to have endless scope for encouraging students to think about their future: in lessons as well as in coaching conversations.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/supporting-new-students-navigating-change-academic-challenge/">Supporting New Students: Navigating Change and Academic Challenge</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/academics">Academics at Halcyon</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/student-life">Student Life at Halcyon</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/ib-student-profile/">IB Student Profile: Lola, Grade 12, on the Diploma Programme</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/cognitive-coaching/">Cognitive Coaching: our Director explains our unique programme to TES</a></p>



<strong>Subscribe to hear more updates on our curriculum, facilities, team and more:<strong>&nbsp;
<!--[if lte IE 8]>
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2-legacy.js"></script>
<![endif]-->
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2.js"></script>
<script>
  hbspt.forms.create({
	portalId: "2990765",
	formId: "db130e02-0e7d-4d18-9c03-c23e70a22958"
});
</script></strong></strong>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 reasons why we’re all trained in Cognitive Coaching</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/coaching/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halcyon London International School]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 08:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Student Wellbeing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=13912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At Halcyon London International School, every member of staff &#8211; teaching, leadership, and administration &#8211; is trained in Cognitive Coaching. Every student has an assigned mentor, and spends a weekly coaching session with them, engaging in conversations that help them plan and reflect on their academic performance, behaviour, strengths and weaknesses, and involvement in school [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At Halcyon London International School, every member of staff &#8211; teaching, leadership, and administration &#8211; is trained in Cognitive Coaching. Every student has an assigned mentor, and spends a weekly coaching session with them, engaging in conversations that help them plan and reflect on their academic performance, behaviour, strengths and weaknesses, and involvement in school life.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>We are the only school in the world to train every member of staff in Cognitive Coaching &#8211; a <a href="https://www.tes.com/magazine/leadership/staff-management/why-all-our-staff-are-trained-cognitive-coaches" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wellbeing practice</a> that our Director answered some questions about in TES magazine. </p>



<p>As a form of mentoring, our Cognitive Coaching programme does more than guide students in the right direction: it teaches them to guide themselves, and flourish in the world as confident, independent, and impactful individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093711.920-1024x682.jpg" alt="coaching in practice" class="wp-image-13913" width="1000" height="666" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093711.920-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093711.920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093711.920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093711.920-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093711.920-600x400.jpg 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093711.920.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure></div>



<h2>What is Cognitive Coaching?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>“The mission of Cognitive Coaching is to produce self-directed persons with the cognitive capacity for excellence both independently and as members of a community.”</p>



<p>As educators, we are responsible for developing students’ skills, as well as their knowledge: their capacities in thinking, collaboration, communication, and creativity. As an International Baccalaureate school, we commit to the mission of producing “young people who help to create a better and more peaceful world” &#8211; and being able to think critically and reflectively about the experiences they encounter through life will support our students in fulfilling this goal.</p>



<p>Cognitive Coaching &#8211; a process in which a trained Cognitive Coach leads a coachee through a structured reflective or planning conversation &#8211; encourages students, the coachees, to become critical thinkers and problem solvers. When a student wishes to discuss a problem they find challenging, the Cognitive Coach does not aim to present a solution, or explain why the problem occurred &#8211; instead, the Cognitive Coach asks meditative questions that guide the student in exploring causal factors, perspectives, and strategies for the future on their own behalf.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cognitive Coaching enables us to maintain a healthy and balanced approach to problem-solving not only as we navigate education and our careers, but also in situations that impact our personal wellbeing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This cognitive development can be life-changing for young people and adults alike.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Enabling teachers to improve their pedagogic practice through coaching</h2>



<p>Our teachers seek to be the best that they can &#8211; and so do our students. through asking learners questions in the right way, our teachers are adept at building young persons’ capacity for self-assessment, bringing them to find their own strengths and weaknesses instead of relying on reports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond evaluating a student’s work, providing an opinion on their progress, or inferring something about their attitude to work, our teachers encourage students to do this themselves. Teachers make observations and ask reflective questions about students’ work to prompt a higher level of thinking &#8211; and we’re pleased to say that this is a successful approach in the classroom.</p>



<p>What does this look like? Instead of saying “Good job!” or “Do you think you could improve you time management skills?”, our teachers might say: “How do you think that went?” or “You didn’t complete the task in the time given.” Driving young people to make their own evaluations and conclusions prepares them to be impactful, self-driven individuals in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Being trained in the art of questioning extends to tone of voice, too, ensuring that our students feel welcome and encouraged to reflect on their progress &#8211; being an approachable educator &#8211; is paramount for our classroom teachers.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="682" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093704.453-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-13914" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093704.453-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093704.453-300x200.jpg 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093704.453-768x512.jpg 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093704.453-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093704.453-600x400.jpg 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093704.453.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>



<h2>Producing self-directed learners with a stronger sense of wellbeing</h2>



<p>In a Cognitive Coaching conversation, coaches pose questions and guide coachees in a deliberate, directed, and targeted way to support them in becoming the best that they can be.<br><br>Coaches seek to develop within their coachees the five ‘States of Mind’: Consciousness, Interdependence, Efficacy, Flexibility, and Craftmanship. These states of mind are all part of being a self-directed learner that can problem-solve and work well with others, and coaches often pose questions that encourage coachees to think about how they can develop these qualities.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="682" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093654.811-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-13915" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093654.811-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093654.811-300x200.jpg 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093654.811-768x512.jpg 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093654.811-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093654.811-600x400.jpg 600w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unnamed-2022-09-06T093654.811.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>



<h2>Facilitating a better learning and working environment through peer-coaching</h2>



<p>Ensuring that every teacher is a trained Cognitive Coach also enables peer-coaching: teachers can support one another in reflecting on their strengths and weaknesses, as well as guiding their thoughts to help plan lessons, units, and time management over the course of a year.&nbsp;This also has a positive effect on <a href="https://www.tes.com/magazine/leadership/staff-management/wellbeing-around-world-removing-heads-subjects" target="_blank" rel="noopener">staff wellbeing</a>. </p>



<p>At Halcyon, peer coaching has nurtured a culture of shared responsibility for research, innovation, and constant improvement. And as we look to the future, we can’t wait for more families to enjoy a Halcyon education.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/supporting-new-students-navigating-change-academic-challenge/">Supporting New Students: Navigating Change and Academic Challenge</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/academics">Academics at Halcyon</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/student-life">Student Life at Halcyon</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/ib-student-profile/">IB Student Profile: Lola, Grade 12, on the Diploma Programme</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/cognitive-coaching/">Cognitive Coaching: our Director explains our unique programme to TES</a></p>



<strong>Subscribe to hear more updates on our curriculum, facilities, team and more:<strong>&nbsp;
<!--[if lte IE 8]>
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2-legacy.js"></script>
<![endif]-->
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2.js"></script>
<script>
  hbspt.forms.create({
	portalId: "2990765",
	formId: "db130e02-0e7d-4d18-9c03-c23e70a22958"
});
</script></strong></strong>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secondary School of the Year: Halcyon Wins EduFuturists Award</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/secondary-school-of-the-year/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halcyon London International School]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 15:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Educational Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=13727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have some excellent news to end the school year: we are the winners of EduFuturists &#8216;Secondary School of the Year&#8217; award! We were honoured to be presented with this award at such a prestigious event, attended by educational technology innovators in the UK and all over the world. You can watch a full recording of the ceremony here. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We have some excellent news to end the school year: we are the winners of <a href="https://hs.halcyonschool.com/e3t/Ctc/GB+113/cl-Fy04/VVvKp03FdLkjW4c_GwN3SkMd_W3hB9jJ4LY4cBN5g75j13q3npV1-WJV7CgNmJW6sJPyL22kXytW4kB2yy36SzGsW1XF0Gr8Y2VB6W4fVRCN1ndZ5sW75rZJq4yFcCbV9KkR410MhhfMwD2-rV3tJQW8JFPDf8_vfwqW23J7bM2DL0LGW6dFzZ51CJtZfW5kyw7L54lRD5W2-8QJt1GtGYBW61csF35854GYW2VbT_X7NGkhJW131_FW89rJQNW5C7tfP16_hVBW4fQhfZ2Kkkl9W2VPmbW92pR4bW7K23Gj54Pg3SW6nlmZl88SBnkW6mkPNY5qWPTfW2Ln1hJ8FlFxV3hNG1" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">EduFuturists</a> &#8216;Secondary School of the Year&#8217; award! We were honoured to be presented with this award at such a prestigious event, attended by educational technology innovators in the UK and all over the world. You can watch a full recording of the ceremony <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BXIVpOh1oyk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>. </p>



<p>We would like to give a special thank you to Halcyon&#8217;s talented teachers, students, and our Digital Learning Coach, Faye Ellis, who provides unique insights, ideas, and inspiration to our community every week. Our dedicated and talented staff team is championing our school&#8217;s innovative spirit, proudly integrating new findings in the world of educational technology into their pedagogy every day, and maintaining a willingness to debate ideas around learning that have remained unchallenged for too long. </p>



<h2>Independent Schools of the Year Awards</h2>



<p>We have also been shortlisted for the following award: Small Independent School of the Year! Last year, we were a finalist in the category of &#8216;Best British International School&#8217;, and we&#8217;re thankful that the Independent Schools of the Year Awards continues to recognise our mission and our achievements. </p>



<p>This is a proud year for Halcyon’s community. In 2022, we revealed our Five-Year Plan, including our goals to spread to a new campus and open a primary school. In September 2023, it will be the tenth anniversary since Halcyon’s opening, and this year’s five-year-out alumni reunion highlighted how much our community has shaped the lives of young people in such a short period of time. </p>



<p>We look forward to keeping you updated on the results!</p>



<h2>Secondary School of the Year: IBDP Results 2022</h2>



<p>We are delighted to share the <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/ib-dp-results-2022/">Class of 2022’s IB Diploma Programme/IB DP results</a>. Our graduates have excelled, and we are so very proud of their achievements.</p>



<p><strong>More on digital at Halcyon and technology in schools:</strong></p>



<ul><li><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/edtech-digital-technology/">EdTech: Our Director Argues For A New Approach in UK Schools</a></li><li><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/science-facilities-at-halcyon/">Science Facilities at Halcyon: Tools to investigate our world</a></li><li><a href="video: Academia at Halcyon">VIDEO: Academia at Halcyon</a></li></ul>



<strong>Subscribe to hear more updates on our curriculum, facilities, team and more:<strong>&nbsp;
<!--[if lte IE 8]>
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2-legacy.js"></script>
<![endif]-->
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2.js"></script>
<script>
  hbspt.forms.create({
	portalId: "2990765",
	formId: "db130e02-0e7d-4d18-9c03-c23e70a22958"
});
</script></strong></strong>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Class of 2022 Update: IB DP Results are in!</title>
		<link>https://halcyonschool.com/blog/ib-dp-results-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Halcyon London International School]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 13:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Baccalaureate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Student Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://halcyonschool.com/?p=13696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are delighted to share the Class of 2022’s IB Diploma Programme/IB DP results. Our graduates have excelled, and we are so very proud of their achievements. They have been guided by the sense of community and purpose at Halcyon &#8211; belonging to a vibrant learning community in pursuit of academic excellence and personal fulfilment. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We are delighted to share the Class of 2022’s IB Diploma Programme/IB DP results. Our graduates have excelled, and we are so very proud of their achievements. They have been guided by the sense of community and purpose at Halcyon &#8211; belonging to a vibrant learning community in pursuit of academic excellence and personal fulfilment. They have supported and encouraged one another to realise their unique potential, and been nurtured by our extraordinarily talented and dedicated staff team. Each of our graduates has been rewarded with a wonderful set of results &#8211; results which have opened doors to the best universities around the world.</p>



<p>Everyone in our community would like to send their warmest congratulations to the graduating Class of 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>IB DP Results Highlights</h2>



<ul><li>34 students sat the IB Diploma</li><li>100% pass rate</li><li>an average points score of 36 </li><li>Highest point score awarded was 45 (out of 45)</li><li>25% of students scored 40 points and higher</li></ul>



<div style="height:39px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="900" height="600" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Results-Day-Stats-Template-2022-EMAIL-HEADER.png" alt="" class="wp-image-13779" srcset="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Results-Day-Stats-Template-2022-EMAIL-HEADER.png 900w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Results-Day-Stats-Template-2022-EMAIL-HEADER-300x200.png 300w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Results-Day-Stats-Template-2022-EMAIL-HEADER-768x512.png 768w, https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Results-Day-Stats-Template-2022-EMAIL-HEADER-600x400.png 600w" sizes="(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /></figure></div>



<div style="height:40px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p>With a 100% pass rate, the 34 graduates of the Class of 2022 have completed their journey at Halcyon together, and will, no doubt, keep in close touch as they go forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our graduates are attending universities all around the world, including: the University of St Andrews, Edinburgh University, the USC Gordon S. Marshall School of Business, the Instituto Marangoni in Milan, the University of Bristol, and the ESSEC Business School in France, to name just a few <a href="https://halcyonschool.com/success/#destinations">destinations</a>. Earlier this year, our University and Careers Counselling Director Asil Al-Shammari remarked on the “<a href="https://halcyonschool.com/blog/university-and-the-ib/">coveted and competitive</a>” nature of some of the courses in which our graduates will be enrolling.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>IB DP Results Average: Past Three Years</h2>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://halcyonschool.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Results-Day-Stats-Template-2022-EMAIL-HEADER-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-13781" width="941" height="360"/></figure></div>



<p></p>



<h2>The Diploma Programme: a future-readying education&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The Class of 2022 is prepared to make a difference in the world that awaits them. The award of the IB Diploma is unique in this sense: it “pushes young people out into the world to confront inequalities and injustice, to be a part of a solution, to learn practical compassion, and find out about themselves and their place in the world”, as stated in our <a href="https://www.teachingtimes.com/our-a-levels-system-isnt-preparing-pupils-for-university-or-life-academically-or-emotionally/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Director’s article in the Teaching Times</a>.</p>



<p>They are beginning their higher education journey equipped with the communication skills, collaboration skills, and critical thinking skills that they will need to navigate the complexities of our future, and we are proud to have been a part of their stories. Our team delivers a pioneering and academic curriculum that is uniquely shaped to confront <a href="https://www.hamhigh.co.uk/news/halcyon-london-on-teaching-climate-change-8472640" target="_blank" rel="noopener">real-world challenges</a> in the context of interdisciplinary investigation, and the achievements and goals of the Class of 2022 are a testament to our community’s success.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congratulations to this cohort on their IB DP results &#8211; and watch this space for news from the Class of 2022 as they prepare for their first year of university!</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/success/">Success Stories at Halcyon</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/academics/">Academics at Halcyon</a></p>



<p><a href="https://halcyonschool.com/meet-the-team/">Meet the Team</a></p>



<strong>Subscribe to hear more updates on our curriculum, facilities, team and more:<strong>&nbsp;
<!--[if lte IE 8]>
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2-legacy.js"></script>
<![endif]-->
<script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/v2.js"></script>
<script>
  hbspt.forms.create({
	portalId: "2990765",
	formId: "db130e02-0e7d-4d18-9c03-c23e70a22958"
});
</script></strong></strong>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Page is feed) 

Served from: halcyonschool.com @ 2023-03-15 17:31:13 by W3 Total Cache
-->